# MUSTAPHA LATEB

Website: mlateb.github.io | GitHub: mlateb

Email: <u>mustapha.lateb@gmail.com</u> Adress: Tizi-Ouzou, Algeria

Phone: +213 552 413 491

#### INTRODUCTION

Graduated, both, in **Environment** and in **Geoinformation**. My research is mainly on Landcover change and forest fire mapping using satellite Remote Sensing and GIS.

Fan of **Data science**, I like to investigate new Image Processing, Machine Learning, Statistics and Timeseries Analysis techniques.

My most used tools are Python and its Geospatial libraries, QGIS, Bash, SQL, HTML, CSS and Git.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

- Jan 2017-Jun 2019: **Researcher** at the *Geoinformation in Environmental Management* departement, *Mediterranean Agronomic Institute of Chania* MAICh.
- Mar 2013-Sep 2013: Energy Steward at Aldaph-NovoNordisk, Tizi-Ouzou, Algeria
- Nov 2011-Feb 2013: Quality Assurance Technician at Aldaph-NovoNordisk, Tizi-Ouzou, Algeria

### **EDUCATION**

- 2016 current : *Doctoral candidate*, **Geoinformation applied to Plant Ecology**, Mouloud Mammeri University of Tizi-Ouzou MMTO, Algeria *Topic:* Multitemporal landcover mapping
- 2013 2016: M. Sc. Degree (2 years), Geoinformation in Environmental Management, MAICh, Greece
  Thesis topic: "Development of an object-based classification model for monitoring treeline shifting, using aerial photography"
- 2011-2014: Magister degree (2 years), Applied Plant Ecology and Environmental Management, UMMTO, Algeria
  Thesis topic: "Study of oak hybridisation using Geometric Morphometric (Landmark Method)"
- 2006 2011 : *Ingénieur d'Etat (5 years)*, **Plant ecology and Environment** UMMTO, Algeria *Thesis topic*: "Inventory of oak gallings and evaluation their impact on forest stands"
- 2008 2011 : Senior Technician (3 years), Database Management INSFP, Algeria Thesis topic: " Creation of a Dynamic Website "

#### ORGANIZATIONAL SKILLS

I was member of the organising committee of the two following international conferences:

- 38th Annual EARSeL Symposium on Earth Observation Supporting Sustainability Research 9-12 July 2018 Chania, Crete, Greece
- 11th EARSeL Forest Fires SIG Workshop on New Trends in Forest Fire Research Incorporating Big Data and Climate Change Modeling 25-27 September 2017, Chania, Greece

# PROGRAMMING SKILLS

- Geospatial processing: Python (MITx 6.00.1x certificate) (Rasterio, Pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, Seaborn, geopandas, Shapely, ...)
- Version controle: Git
- Database: SQL
- Web design:  $\mathsf{HTML}$  ,  $\mathsf{CSS}$ ,  $\mathsf{Markdown}$  Softwares:  $\mathsf{QGIS}$ ,  $\mathsf{eCognition}$ ,  $\mathsf{ArcGIS}$ ,  $\mathsf{ERDAS}$ ,  $\mathsf{MapInfo}$
- Operating systems: Linux & Windows

## LANGUAGES

Kabyle: Mother tongue English: TOEFL ITP French: Fluent Arabic: Fluent Greek: Beginner